James Simmons papers, 1945-1996
Emory University
- Writings by Simmons, circa 1962-1999, Series 3; Boxes 23-52, OP 1-4
  - Prose, Subseries 3.2; Boxes 31-43
    - "Patriots 20th Century," TS (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - "Poetic and Scientific Language," TS (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - "Poetry," TS (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - "Poetry: Lecture I," MS (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - "Prose: Last Lecture," TS (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - "Prose: Lecture 2," TS (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - "Prose: Lecture 3," TS (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - " The Rainbow," TSS (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - " The Real Charlotte," MS and TS (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - "Recent Poetry in Ulster," TS (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - "Reform in English Studies," TS (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - "The Renaissance/The Reformation," TS (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - "Revolution, Progress, Politics," TS (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - "Romanticism," MSS and TSS (Box 42, Folder 34)
    - "Sam Hanna Bell: December Bride," MS and TS (Box 42, Folder 35)
    - "Sample of Demonstrably Bad Verse," TS (Box 42, Folder 36)
    - "Samuel Beckett," MSS and TSS (Box 42, Folder 37)
    - "Sean O'Faolain," MSS and TSS (Box 42, Folder 38)
    - "Shakespeare," TS (Box 42, Folder 39)
    - " Six Characters in Search of an Author," TS (Box 42, Folder 40)
    - " Sons and Lovers," MSS and TSS (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - "The Special Place of English in the University," TSS (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - "Speech for the 25th Anniversary of The Honest Ulsterman," TS (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - "Spencer," MS (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - "The Study of Literature," TS (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Synge," TSS (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - "Synge in the Gaelic World," TS (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - "Themes of Democracy," MSS and TSS (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - "Thomas Hardy," MS (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "Translations from the Gaelic," TS (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - "T.S. Eliot," MS and TS (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - " Ulysses," MSS and TSS (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - " Waiting for Godot," MS and TSS (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - "William Blake," TS (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - "William Carleton, Denis OShaugnessy Goes to Maynooth," TS (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - " Women of Trachis," TS (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "Wordsworth," MS (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "Yeats," MSS and TSS (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - "Yeats on the Anglo-Irish Tradition," TS (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Untitled (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Untitled (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Songs, Subseries 3.3; Boxes 44-45
    - "Anna Rebecca Foley Simmons," MS and TSS (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "The Anniversary Song," TS (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Baby, Baby," TSS (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "Ballad," TS (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Ballad of Claudy," TS (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "A Ballad for Commonwealth Day," TS (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "The Ballad of Gerry Kelly the Newsagent," TS (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Ballad of Ranger Best," MS and TS (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - "The Bard of Armagh," TS (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "Beautiful City," TS (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "The Big Long Bender," TSS (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "Birthday Song for Marjorie," MSS (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - "The Boys of Londonderry," TS (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - "The Carpenter's Wife," MS (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - "Character Song," TS (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - "Crucifixion Story Thinly Disguised," TS (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "The County Antrim," TS (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "Deep in Love," MS (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - "The Docks at Londonderry," TSS (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - "Donegal," TS (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - "Don't Like to be Living This Way," TS [variant title: "Dissatisfaction"] (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - "Drinker's Blues," TSS (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - "Drinking Song," TS (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - "Edith Cavell," TS (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - "Elegy No. 3," TS (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - "The Emigrant's Ticket," TSS (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - "Familiarity," MS and TS [variant title: "More Familiar With You"] (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - "The Feakler's Anthem," TS (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - "For George," TSS (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - "Frankie and Johnny Got Married," TS (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - "The Freedom from Hunger Song," TSS (Box 44, Folder 32)
    - "Friendly Oul' Drink," TS (Box 44, Folder 33)
    - "The Girl from Aghalee," TSS (Box 44, Folder 34)
    - "Girl of My Dreams," TSS (Box 44, Folder 35)
    - "The God Children are Sleeping," TSS (Box 44, Folder 36)
    - "The Good Ship Six Counties," TS (Box 44, Folder 37)
    - "Greencastle," TS (Box 44, Folder 38)
    - "Hard Drinking Song," TS (Box 44, Folder 39)
    - "The Hard Man," MS (Box 44, Folder 40)
    - "Harp Song of the Dane Women," TS (Box 44, Folder 41)
    - "Have You Been to Derry?," TS (Box 44, Folder 43)
    - "Hitch-A-Lift Jim," TSS (Box 44, Folder 44)
    - "Holiday in Garvagh," TS (Box 44, Folder 45)
    - "How is the Weather?," TS (Box 44, Folder 46)
    - "The Humanists' Drinking Song," TS (Box 44, Folder 47)
    - "I Wanna Beer," TS (Box 44, Folder 48)
    - "The Idiom of the People," MS (Box 44, Folder 49)
    - "If People Had Courage," MS (Box 44, Folder 50)
    - "In the Bleak Midwinter," TS (Box 44, Folder 51)
    - "Janice," TS (Box 44, Folder 52)
    - "Janice and Me," TS (Box 44, Folder 53)
    - "Jerusalem," TSS (Box 44, Folder 54)
    - "Johnny I Hardly Knew You," TS (Box 44, Folder 55)
    - "Johnny My Gigolo," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman] (Box 44, Folder 56)
    - "Kensington Gardens Square," TSS (Box 44, Folder 57)
    - "Kill the Children," TS (Box 44, Folder 58)
    - "The Lascar and the Baby," MSS and TSS (Box 44, Folder 59)
    - "Let This Cup Pass From Me," TS (Box 44, Folder 60)
    - "Lift Me and Lay Me," TS (Box 44, Folder 61)
    - "Loneliness," TS (Box 44, Folder 62)
    - "Lot's Wife," TS (Box 44, Folder 63)
    - "Love," TSS (Box 44, Folder 64)
    - "Love in the Post," TS (Box 44, Folder 65)
    - "Mabel's Song," TSS (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "Mansion By the Sea," MS and TSS (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "March," TS (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Marie C. Stopes," TS (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "Mild Political Portraits," TS (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "Mr. Mooney," TSS (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "Navvy Boots," TSS (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "The Next Market Day," TS (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "1983," MS (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "No Heroes Like Him in Belfast," TS (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "No Room at the Inn," TS (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "No Tengo Mas Que Dar Te," TS (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "The Old Lady's Song," TSS (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - "Old Pub's Song," TS (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - "Our Family," TS [See Subseries 3.3, Songs, "I Wanna Beer"] (Box 45)
    - "Pacific Blues," TS (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "Parce que," TS (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "Peace Song," TS (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "The Plumber's Wife," TS (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "Portrush Song," MSS and TSS (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - "The Professional Abroad," TS (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - "The Pub Song," TS (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "Ramble Away," TSS [See also Subseries 3.3, Songs, "Mansion by the Sea" MS] (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - "Ronadaine Cary," TS (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - "The School Teacher," TSS (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - "The Sea," TSS (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - "The Senator and the Admiral," TS (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - "Shame," TS (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - "Sheikh Mahammed's Song on the Leath of Corfield," TS (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - "The Sherry Song," TS (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - "Song," TS (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - "Songs for Easter '74," TS (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - "The Spanish Lady," TS (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - "A Speech for the Clown," TS (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - "The Sporting Races at Galways," TS (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - "Spring Song," TSS (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - "Stinson at the Bridge," TS (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - "The Sun," TSS (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - "Three Pornographers," TSS (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - "Topicalities," TSS (Box 45, Folder 39)
    - "The Travelling Man and a Growing Girl," TS (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - "The Ulster Soldier Boy," TS (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - "Unemployment in the Eighties," TS (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - "The Unfortunate Role," MS (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - "We're Really Very Lucky," TS (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - "Where's Garvin?," MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 45)
    - "A Woman's Company," TSS (Box 45, Folder 46)
    - "The Young Airforce Men," TSS (Box 45, Folder 47)
    - "Young Peter Thompson," TSS (Box 45, Folder 48)
    - Untitled (Box 45, Folder 49)
  - Translations, Subseries 3.4; Box 46
    - "Blodewedd," TSS (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "Dun," TSS [Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill's "Dun"] (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - "Father," TS [Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill] (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - "If I Were to Die Out There," TS [Apollinaire's "Si Je Mourrais La-bas"] (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - "The Lady from Aragon," TS [Joan-Manuel Serrat's "La Dama d'Arago"] (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "Les Poetes," TS [Louis Aragon] [See Subseries 3.4, Translations, "If I Were to Die Out There"]
    - "Listening in the Morning," TSS [Bert Voeten's "Luisteren in de Ochtend"] (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "The Nightingale," TS [Joan-Manuel Serrat's "El Rossinyol"] [See Subseries 3.4, Translations, "The Lady from Aragon]
    - "Our Castles are Ruins or Hotels," TS [Nuala Ní Dhomahnaill] (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - "Song of the Thief," TS [Joan-Manuel Serrat's "La Caco del Lladre"] [See Subseries 3.4, Translations, "The Lady from Aragon]
    - "The Sun on My Hand," TSS [Bert Voeten's "De Zon Op Mijn Hand"] (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "Together Again," TSS [Vroomkoning's "Hereniging"] (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - "The Yellow Bittern," TSS (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks, Subseries 3.5; Box 47 - Box 52: folders 1-5
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from Ballad of a Marriage, Late But in Earnest, In the Wilderness, Energy to Burn, Long Summer Still to Come, Judy Garland and the Cold War, and From the Irish] [includes correspondence] (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from In the Wilderness and Energy to Burn] (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from Constantly Singing and Mainstream] (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from Sex, Rectitude, and Loneliness] (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from Mainstream] (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from Mainstream] (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from Mainstream] (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes poetry from The Company of Children] (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with Poetry [includes songs and poetry from The Company of Children] (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with proofs of Constantly Singing (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Notebook with Poetry (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Notebook with Poetry and clippings of poetry by others (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with Poetry and Prose (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with Poetry and Prose (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with Poetry and Prose (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with Poetry and Songs (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with draft of The Gambler (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Notebook with drafts of Have You Been to Derry? (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Notebook with drafts of Ulster Portraits (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Notebook with draft of untitled novella (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Notebook with Prose (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Notebook with Songs (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Notebook with Songs (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Notebook with notes on T.S. Eliot and Lionel Trilling (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with notes on Sean O'Casey (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with notes on W.B. Yeats (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with notes on Irish Literature (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with notes for lectures (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with notes on and pictures of singers (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with school chemistry notes (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with transcriptions of poetry by others (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with transcriptions and clippings of poetry by others (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with transcriptions and clippings of poetry by others (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Works edited by Simmons, Subseries 3.6; Box 52: folder 6
    - The Honest Ulsterman, Number 1, May 1968; materials for first issue [includes: first issue of The Honest Ulsterman, typescripts of works included, Stevie Smith's "A Soldier Dear to Us," Brenden Kennelly's "The Stones," and "A Man in Yellow Oilskin," John D. Stewart's, "Let Us Be Human," John Hewitt's "From the Tibetan," Derek Mahon's "A Dying Art," and "Ecclesiastes," John Hearsum's "The Running of Things," W. Price Turner's "Full Supporting Programme," Michael Stephens's "Interview with Roger McGough," and "Drugs V. Drink," Peter Lewis's "A Tale of a Turd," Mary O' Malley's "Irish Theatre Letter," W. Price Turner's "Procrastination," and James Simmons's "Johnny My Gigolo" as well as MSS and TSS of works submitted but not used in the first issue, including Micheal Brophy's "Dance Little Man," "Death in the Glen," and "Flowers," Daniel Burleigh's "Bird," John Cassidy's "Love Seen," Stanley Cromie's "Philby," and "Specialization," Raymond Ellis's "Elegy on the Death of Martin Luther King," and "Yet Another Odyssey," Gavin Ewart's "Broadstairs," "The Dickens Wife," "The Seven Stages," and "A Vision," Padriac Fiacc's "Morning Dark," and "Vengenance," Micheal Friel's "Gransha," N.N. Glancy's "Irish Medical Lore," James Greer's "Awakening," John Hewitt's "Alec of the Chimney Corner," and "The Search," W.J. Holland, "A Short Piece of Friction," Brenden Kennelly, "Birthdays and Farewells," and "A Couple," Derek Mahon's "Fall-Out," "The Graduate in Metal Bose," and "Tragic Hero of Our Time," Martin, Hazel, "Folk Song," and "Magilligan," McFeeter, Gerry, "Poem for the Womanhood of Today," James Michie's "The Martial," Derek Montgomery's "Letter from America," O'Connor, Fleann, "Salvage," Jon O'Kelly's "Maximum Content and Minimum Hered," "Ponderessur," "Romance," "A Talent Lost is a Tear Hidden," and "A Worthy Troubadour," Denise Robertson's "Pit Closure," Jon Squires's "Aisling," "The Campaign," "My Friend," and "West-North-West," Michael Stephens's "I Think It Was Michael Stephens Who Said...," "The Importance of Free Thought," "My Noddy Neurosis," and "Schooldays," and W. Price Turner's "The Moral Rocking-Horse," "A Northern Tragedy," "Prop and Prodder," "The Queer Spleen Face," and "Rose Harem"] (Box 52, Folder 6)
- Subject files, 1988-1997, Series 4; Boxes 53-64, OP 5-10
  The subject files in the James Simmons papers were not arranged by Simmons but were artificially assembled out of similar materials found throughout the papers. Subseries 4.1, The Poets' House files contain materials that describe the program's concept and the many obstacles that the Simmons's faced during the planning and running of The Poets' House. Types of records include correspondence, administrative, faculty, and student files, scrapbooks, printed material, and drafts of poems included in At Six O'Clock in the Silence of Things..: A Festschrift for James Simmons, a tribute to James Simmons printed by the Poets' House in 1993. Subseries 4.2 contains other subject files such as Aosdána, the Hobsbaum Group, drawings by Simmons, and his father's navy documents. This Subseries also contains many of Simmons's personal items such as passports, driver's licenses, school report cards, and divorce papers.
  Organized into two subseries: (4.1) The Poets' House files and (4.2) Other subject files.
  - Poets' House files, Subseries 4.1; Boxes 53-61; OP 5-9
    - Correspondence
    - 1988-1990 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - 1991 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - 1992 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - January-June, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - July-December, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - January-June, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - July-December, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - January-June, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - July-December, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Administrative files
    - Address to Larne Council, Re: Planning permission (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Board of Advisors meeting notes (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Comments on The Poets' House (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Conference schedules (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Course evaluations (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Description of M.A. Irish Language Module (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Description of The Poets' House (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Financial papers (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Grant proposal (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Lancaster University, Guidelines for Associated Institutions (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Letterhead (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - M.A. Lecture notes (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - M.A. student assignment (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Mailing lists (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Photographs (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Poetry groups and workshops in and around London (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Press releases (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Progress report, Sept 1995 (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - Report on Poets' House M.A. Course by Bernard O'Donoghue, External Examiner, 1993-1996 (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Rules of the Poets' House (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Student Questionnaires, 1994 Summer Sessions (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Summer Conferences: Student list (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Faculty files
    - Collins, Billy (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Gillian, Pamela (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Gough, Damien (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - McBreen, Joan (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Meehan, Paula (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Simmons, James (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Simmons, Janice Fitzpatrick (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Faculty Applications (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Student files
    - Bingham, Alyson (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Burroughs, Mary (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Cafolla, Terry (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Carville, Daragh (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Connelly, Catherine (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - de Freine, Celia (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Donovan, Matt (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Dunlap, Stephanie (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Fox, Adrian (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - French, Tom (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Gaitzel, Kitty (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Gallagher, Colette (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Garbett, Ann Davison (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Graham, Cathy (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Granier, Mark (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Grattan, Paul (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Handler, Joan Cusack (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Harris, Carl (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Hess, Arlan (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Hethcoat, Amy (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Horner, David (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Keller, David (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Kinnarney, Bill (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Mason, David (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - McCarthy, Phil (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - McCoole, Eric (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - McDowell, Hilary (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - McGinn, Audrey (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - McGovern, Iggy (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Meeds, Bridget (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - Mitchell-Foust, Michelle (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Murphy, Pauline (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Murray, Joel (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Nonaka, Miho (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - O'Hagan, Sheila (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - O'Hare, Francis (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - O'Hern, James (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - O'Toole, Kathleen (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Okemwe, Christopher (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Ryals, Mary Jane (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Scott, Margaret (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Sheard, Norma Voorhees (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Sinclair, Maureen (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Snyder, Gary (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Tinley, Bill (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Turlde, Ann (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Varrone, Kevin (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Vennard, Myra (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Vial, Noelle (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Wavle, Robert (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Wood,, Heather (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Woods, Joe (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - M.A. Examiner Notes (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Unidentified Student Poems (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - At Six O'Clock in the Silence of Things..: A Festschrift for James Simmons (1993)
    - Bruce, Eloise, "Lines for Jimmy," TS (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Craig, David, "Go as Far as You Can," TSS (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Dibdin, Michael, "Was That The Week That Was?," TS (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Dorgan, Theo, "Morning, The Poets' House in Portmuck," TS (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Gillian, Pamela, "Convergence," TS (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Kavanagh, P.J., "James: The Moore of Ireland," TS (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - McBreen, Joan, "The Iris Garden," TS (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - McCarthy, Donal, "In the Lock Up," TS (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - McCarthy, Thomas, "James Simmons and Martin Luther in the Larne District," TS (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, "Two Heliotropes," TS (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Meehan, Paula, "Folktale," TS (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Mooney, Martin, "Off the Back of a Lorry," TS (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Newmann, Joan, "Man Dancing in a Lighted Window," TSS (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - O'Toole, Bridget, "A Good Place to Be," TS (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Ormsby, Frank, "The Copper Beech," TS (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Ormsby, Frank, "The Gap on My Shelf," TS (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Santos, Sherod, "A Collage for James Simmons on His Sixtieth Birthday," TS (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Simmons, James, "Outing to Port-A-Doris," TSS (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Simmons, Janice, "Dancing on the Roof," TS (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Simmons, Janice, "Settler," TS (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Spillard, Anne, "Eating Pheasant," TSS (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Book jacket material (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Scrapbooks
    - June 1991 (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - July 1991 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box OP5)
    - Printed material
    - At Six O'Clock in the Silence of Things...: A Festschrift for James Simmons (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - "Council Disagree Over 'Poet's House' Planning," by Steven McAlister in Larne Gazette, 17 April 1996 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - "Down Islandmagee Way is Where Poetic Champions Compose," by Mark Ashby, 9 January 1991 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - "Dream Come True for Poets," in Donegal People's Press, 7 May 1997 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - "Haven for Culture at Portmuck," by Neil Johnston in Belfast Telegraph, 15 January 1991 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - "Head for Heights," by Tess Hurson in Ulster Newsletter, 22 July 1991 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - "Heaney Takes His Ease in Islandmagee," in The Irish News, 20 July 1991 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - "The Hedge School of Portmuck," by Katie Donovan in The Irish Times, 8 August 1995 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - "High 'School' for Poets..." by Neil Johnston in Belfast Telegraph, 17 June 1992 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - "Islandmagee Poet Plays Host," by Neil Johnston in Belfast Telegraph, 28 February 1991 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - "James' Verse Vacations," by Neil Johnston in Belfast Telegraph (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - "New Blow for Poets' House," in the Times, 16 January 1996 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - "Open Door at Poets' House," by Tess Hurson in UlsterNewsletter, 2 January 1991 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - "Plangent Echo," by Sean Dunne [review of Martin Mooney's Grub] (Box 61, Folder 14)